Guide to the New York State Wine Grape Growers records,1965-1991.
New York State Wine Grape Growers records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State Wine Grape Growers records, 1965-1991.
6714
New York State Wine Grape Growers
4 cubic ft.
Correspondence, Financial Records, Printed Materials, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Records document the activities of the organization. Other items include, member files, grape prices, news items, legislation that pertains to the wine and grape, correspondence with legislators, marketing, Vinefresh, annual meeting items, press releases, and newsletters. Also included are the files of Monty Stamp as secretary to the organization these have meeting minutes, financial information, copies of mailings from the organization.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
New York Wine Grape Growers mission is to benefit in any way possible members and the New York grape industry.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Records document the activities of the organization. Other items include, member files, grape prices, news items, legislation that pertains to the wine and grape, correspondence with legislators, marketing, Vinefresh, annual meeting items, press releases, and newsletters. Also included are the files of Monty Stamp as secretary to the organization these have meeting minutes, financial information, copies of mailings from the organization.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State Wine Grape Growers; Stamp Monty.; Trezise, Jim.; New York Wine & Grape Foundation.
Subjects:
Grape industry--New York (State); Grape juice industry--New York (State); Grape juice--United States.; Grapes.; Liquor laws.; Viticulturists.; Wine and wine making--New York (State).
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also collection #6695 Box 4 for some oversize items from NYWGG including advertising proofs for NY wine and grape campaigns.
See also Cornell Cooperative Extension Finger Lakes Grape Program records, #6773.
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
CONTAINER LIST
- Articles of incorporation, bylaws, trademark (Box 1, Folder 1)
- President of NYSWGG (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Annual meeting, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Annual meeting, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Annual meeting, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Annual meeting, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Annual meeting, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Annual meeting and dinner, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Annual meeting and banquet, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Annual meeting and banquet, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Annual meeting and banquet, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Annual meeting and banquet, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Picnic, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Picnic, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Picnic, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Membership (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Office space 350 Elm Street (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Grape prices, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Grape prices, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Reception, Dave Peterson (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Office operations expenses (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Watkins review (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Financial reports (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Industrial Development Agency Yates County (Box 1, Folder 24)
- IRS application for recognition of exemption (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Various correspondence and records (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Information on Bully Hill Winery by Walter S. Taylor (Box 1, Folder 27)
- New York state winery newsletters (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Award winning wines (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Miscellaneous activities (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Letters (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Profile of the New York Grape Industry, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Wine grower's assignments (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Promotion (Box 1, Folder 34)
- New York Wine and Grape Foundation (Box 1, Folder 35)
- NYSWGG Newsletter - The Vineyard Post, 1981-1988 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- New York Grape Country Cooperative Incorporated, Vinefresh (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Job descriptions, Vinefresh (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Trademarks, Vinefresh (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Wine and grape juice products, Vinefresh and Finger Lakes Finest, 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Members, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Members, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Members, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Members, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Members, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Members, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Members, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Members, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Members, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Members, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Board of Directors (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Board of Directors meeting (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Chron file, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Chron file, Jan - June 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Chron file, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Chron file, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Chron file, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Chron file, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Chron file, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Chron file, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Chron file, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Chron file, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  1983 does not appear to be in material given to Cornell.
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Monty Stamp secretary files, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Executive committee (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Grape prices, 1978-1987 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Grape prices, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Grape prices, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Seagram Company Ltd, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Winegrape press release, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Grape purchasing agreement (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Insurance, employer liability, workmen's compensation (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Marketing order, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Licensing and sale of farm products, Circular 922, article 20, agriculture and markets law (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Grape pricing (Box 4, Folder 11)
- State fair (Box 4, Folder 12)
- New York State sales tax (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Excise tax legislation, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Federal commercial motor vehicle act of, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Chemicals (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Letters from legislators (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Letters from legislators 2 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Wine coolers (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Wine task force report (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Wine legislation (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Testimonies state (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Equalization and assessment (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Alcoholic beverage control act amendment (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Business tax reform and rate reduction act (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Canadian grape prices (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Agricultural use values (Box 4, Folder 27)
- New York wine bottle (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Prompt payment, Circular 922, sale of farm products (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Occupational Safety and Health Administration, Federal Hazard Communication Standard (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Imports - Exports (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Grapes from Canada, import legislation (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, legislation, direct shipping, grape marketing, labeling (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Federal crop insurance (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Cost of production, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Cost of production, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Cost of production, master, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Cost of production, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Market Potential for Finger Lakes Grape Products (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Pledge, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Miscellaneous material (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Correspondence to be preserved (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Market order refunds (Box 4, Folder 43)